The Grim Collection: Hudson River Fisheries Investigation, 1965-1968
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
The Grim Collection: Hudson River Fisheries Investigation
1965 - 1968
NPKMC-222-158
4 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
John Grim
Northeast Biologists, Inc. conducted tests on the Hudson River and it’s fisheries between the years of 1965 and 1968. The collection consists of the findings of Northeast Biologists, Inc., including reports and studies the company compiled over the three-year period.
Related Collections
Collection Overview
The Grim Collection consists of papers, reports, forms and other documents relating to the study performed by Northeast Biologists, Inc., which was conducted on the Hudson River and it’s fisheries from 1965 to 1968.
Included in the collection are fish capture reports, Hudson River temperature studies, daily catch record sheets, and fish, egg and larvae reports.
Acquisitions Information
John Grim presented the records to the Marist College Library in 1997.
Historical Note
Introductory Note By John Grim:
This was a committee directed study. Members of the Committee were made up of representatives of the NYS Conservation department, the N.J. Conservation Department, the Federal Fish and Wildlife Service and Consolidated Edison Company. I believe the State of Connecticut may have contributed a representative later on.
Northeast Biologists, Inc. conducted the first three years of the Hudson River Study. We were not fortunate to get the bid for the second three years and later bids.
John Grim, 2-21-97
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into six series: 1. Introductory Note, instructions for crew chief, and related forms, 2. Indian Point Temperautre Study, 3. Daily Sampling Reports and Daily Catch Record Sheets, 4. Fish Capture Reports and Egg and Larvae Reports, 5. Fish Capture Reports, and 6. Reports and Temperature Studies.
- 1. Introductory Note, Instructions for crew chief, and related forms, 1968; 1; Boxes: 1 - 2 Folders: 1 - 12
  - Introductory Note By John Grim: 2/2/97 (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Instructions for Crew Chief, HRFI, 4/18/68 from F.T. Carlson, &Field Calibration of Meters Sheet (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Blank Forms (list in folder) (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Fish, Egg and Larvae Report, Hudson River (4/23/68 - 5/18/68) (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Fish, Egg and Larvae Report, Hudson River (5/20/68 - 6/5/68) (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - Fish, Egg and Larvae Report, Hudson River (6/6/68 - 6/20/68) (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - Fish, Egg and Larvae Report, Hudson River (6/21/68 - 7/3/68) (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - Fish, Egg and Larvae Report, Hudson River (7/4/68 - 7/16/68) (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River (6/11/68 - 7/22/68) (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River (7/23/68 - 7/31/68) (Folder 10, Box 2)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River (8/1/68 - 8/9/68) (Folder 11, Box 2)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River (8/11/68 - 8/16/68) (Folder 12, Box 2)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River (8/16/68 - 10/10/68) (Folder 13, Box 2)
- 2. Indian Point Temperature Study, 1966 - 1968; 2; Boxes: 3 - 4 Folders: 14 - 36
  - Hudson River, Indian Point Temperature Study (blank forms) (Folder 14, Box 3)
  - Fish Collection Data Sheets: includes stations Croton, Peekskill, Marlboro, Hyde Park, Kingston, Saugerties, and Coxsackie. (Folder 15, Box 3)
  - Fish Collection Data Sheets: station Cornwall (3/66 - 11/66). Seine (Folder 16, Box 3)
  - Fish Collection Data Sheets: Cornwall (6/66 - 11/66) Trawl. (Folder 17, Box 3)
  - Fish Identification Sheets: various stations (8/5/66 - 10/31/66) Seine&Trawl (Folder 18, Box 3)
  - Fish Identification Sheets: various stations (6/14/67 - 12/14/67) Seine&Trawl (Folder 19, Box 3)
  - Fish Identification Sheets: station Cornwall (9/28/68 - 12/8/68) Sampling Station at Cornwall Map (Folder 20, Box 3)
  - Fish Identification Sheets: Indian Point, (6/7/68 - 10/10/68) inventory of the 1968 HRFI Fish Collections (Folder 21, Box 3)
  - Fish, Egg, and Larvae Report, Hudson River, (6/25/68 - 7/3/68) (Folder 22, Box 3)
  - Fish, Egg and Larvae Report, Hudson River, (7/4/68 - 7/16/68 (Folder 23, Box 3)
  - HRFI Samples at USDI; New Windsor, NY: 1966 and 1967 Fish Egg and Larvae (various stations); 1968 Fish Egg, Cornwall: 1968 Fish Larvae, Cornwall (Folder 24, Box 3)
  - HRFI 1966, 1967 and 1968 Cornwall Plankton Samples at NYCD; New Paltz, NY (Folder 25, Box 4)
  - Table I - IV, various locations; Physical&Chemical Data/Striped Bass; Eggs Collected 4/25/66 - 6/16/66, includes graphs (Folder 26, Box 4)
  - Table: Total Catch/Unit of effort of Different Fishes caught 3/18/66 11/15/66 includes graphs (Folder 27, Box 4)
  - Summary of Striped Bass Eggs and Larvae Collection 1966, various stations; STB Larvae collected from the bottom of the Hudson River, 1966; Statement from the University of Maryland; Fish Egg and Larvae Sheet, various locations. (Folder 28, Box 4)
  - Daily Sampling Report-Extended Egg&Larvae Survey (4/19/66 7/15/66) (Folder 29, Box 4)
  - Fish, Egg and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 5/25/68 - 6/3/68 Cornwall (Folder 30, Box 4)
  - Fish, Egg and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 6/4/68 - 6/11/68, Cornwall (Folder 31, Box 4)
  - Fish, Egg and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 6/12/68 - 6/18/68, Cornwall (Folder 32, Box 4)
  - Fish, Egg and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 6/19/68 - 6/24/68, Cornwall (Folder 33, Box 4)
  - Hudson River - Misc. Trawls 1966; Croton Through Hyde Park; Hudson River 1966 - Total Fish Collections by Seine and Trawl in Tidal Water, all stations (Folder 34, Box 4)
  - Fish Species Abbreviations, Annual Fish Collection Summary 1966 - various locations (Folder 35, Box 4)
  - List of Number of Vials per date/per site; Station 8 - 21 Larvae and Egg Collection (Folder 36, Box 4)
- 3. Daily Sampling Reports and Daily Catch Record Sheets, 1965 - 1966; 3; Boxes: 6 - 7 Folders: 1 - 60
  - Introductory Note by John Grim (Folder 37, Box 5)
  - Hudson River Collection Sheet; Cornwall, 9/28/65 - 12/8/65 (Folder 38, Box 5)
  - 1967 Temperature Study Report submitted to Con Edison - Hudson River, Indian Point (Folder 39, Box 5)
  - 1966 Fish Collection; Experimental Trawls, Hudson River Fisheries and Biological Survey; 10/12/66 - 10/20/66 (Folder 40, Box 5)
  - Hudson River - Fisheries and Biological Survey; All Stations; Daily Catch Record Sheets, April 18 to May 19 1966 (Folder 41, Box 5)
  - Daily Sampling Report - Croton, Peekskill (Folder 42, Box 5)
  - Egg and Larvae Sampling - Cornwall (Folder 43, Box 5)
  - Daily Sampling Report - Marlboro, Kingston, Saugerties, Coxsackie (Folder 44, Box 5)
  - Daily Sampling Report - Miscellaneous (Folder 45, Box 5)
  - Hudson River - Fisheries and Biological Survey all stations; Daily Catch Record Sheets; May 20/21 to June 3/4, 1966 (Folder 46, Box 5)
  - Daily Sampling Report - Croton, Peekskill, Cornwall, Marlboro, Hyde Park, Kingston, Saugerties, Coxsackie (Folder 47, Box 5)
  - Hudson River Fisheries and Biological Survey, All Stations; Daily Catch Record Sheets June 5/6 - June 24, 1966 (Folder 48, Box 5)
  - Daily Sampling Report - Croton, Peekskill (Bear Mountain), Cornwall, Marlboro, Hyde Park, Kingston, Saugerties, Coxsackie (Folder 49, Box 5)
  - Hudson River Fisheries and Biological Survey, all stations; Daily Catch Record Sheets; June 25 - July 21, 1966; Final Egg and Larvae Report 1966 (Folder 50, Box 5)
  - Egg and Larvae Sampling Cornwall (Folder 51, Box 5)
  - Daily Sampling Report - Hyde Park, Croton, Peekskill, Marlboro, Kingston, Saugerties, Coxsackie, Misc. (Folder 52, Box 5)
  - Hudson River Fisheries&Biological Survey; Report to the Policy Committee 10/25/66; Daily Catch Record Sheets-Cornwall, 3/18 - 7/31/66 (Folder 53, Box 5)
  - Hudson River Fisheries&Biological Survey; Report to the Policy Committee 11/14/66; Daily Catch Record Sheets, All Stations - 8/1 - 8/15/66 (Folder 54, Box 5)
  - Hudson River Fisheries&Biological Survey; Report to the Policy Committee 11/29/66; Daily Catch Record Sheets, All Stations - 8/16 - 8/31/66 (Folder 55, Box 6)
  - Hudson River Fisheries&Biological Survey; Report to the Policy Committee 12/7/66; Daily Catch Record Sheets, All Stations-9/1 - 9/15/66 (Folder 56, Box 6)
  - Daily Catch Record Sheets, All Stations; 9/16 - 9/30/66 (Folder 57, Box 6)
  - Daily Catch Record Sheets, All Stations; 10/1 - 10/15/66 (Folder 58, Box 6)
  - Daily Catch Record Sheets, All Stations; 10/16 - 10/31/66 (Folder 59, Box 6)
  - Daily Catch Record Sheets, All Stations; 11/1 - 11/15/66 (Folder 60, Box 6)
- 4. Fish Capture Reports and Egg and Larvae Reports, 1966 - 1968; 4; Boxes: 7 - 8 Folders: 61 - 81
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River; Hyde Park, 6/14/67 - 8/24/67, Numbered 1,825 - 1,887 (Folder 61, Box 7)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River; Indian Point, 7/5/67 - 8/9/67, Numbered 1,888 - 1,975 (Folder 62, Box 7)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River; Indian Point, 8/9/67 - 9/1/67, Numbered 1,976 - 2,123 (Folder 63, Box 7)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River; Indian Point, 9/1/67 - 10/7/67, Numbered 2,124 - 2,251 (Folder 64, Box 7)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River; Kingston, 8/11/67 - 9/25/67, Numbered 2,252 - 2,368 (Folder 65, Box 7)
  - Summary of Revised Fish, Egg, and Larvae Report for 1966 (Folder 66, Box 7)
  - Eggs and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 1967; Coxsackie (Folder 67, Box 7)
  - Eggs and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 1967; Saugerties (Folder 68, Box 7)
  - Eggs and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 1967; Kingston (Folder 69, Box 7)
  - Eggs and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 1967; Hyde Park (Folder 70, Box 7)
  - Eggs and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 1967; Marlboro (Folder 71, Box 7)
  - Eggs and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 1967; Peekskill (Folder 72, Box 7)
  - Eggs and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 1967; Cornwall (regular) (Folder 73, Box 7)
  - Eggs and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 1967; Croton (Folder 74, Box 8)
  - Eggs and Larvae Report, Hudson River, 1967; Cornwall 24 hour (Folder 75, Box 8)
  - HRFI - Fish, Egg, and Larvae Report 1967 - Gear Test, Various Locations (Folder 76, Box 8)
  - Egg and Larvae Plankton Sort - 1967, Cornwall (Folder 77, Box 8)
  - HRFI; 1968 Fish, Egg and Larvae Report; book 1 of 4, 4/21 - 5/18 (Folder 78, Box 8)
  - HRFI; 1968 Fish, Egg and Larvae Report; book 2 of 4, 5/19 - 6/8 (Folder 79, Box 8)
  - HRFI; 1968 Fish, Egg and Larvae Report; book 3 of 4, 6/9 - 6/22 (Folder 80, Box 8)
  - HRFI; 1968 Fish, Egg and Larvae Report; book 4 of 4, 6/23 - 7/20 (Folder 81, Box 8)
- 5. Fish Capture Reports, 1966 - 1967; 5; Boxes: 9 - 10 Folders: 82 - 117
  - Hudson River Fisheries 1965-1968: Evaluations of a Proposed Pumped Storage Project at Cornwall, New York in Relation to Fish in the Hudson River (Folder 82, Box 9)
  - Fish Species Abbreviations (Folder 83, Box 9)
  - Fish Capture sheets, collections not available, Cornwall - 1967; Fish Capture Report, Hudson River - 1967; Cornwall (regular) 6/22/67 - 8/21/67; Numbered 1,191 - 1,318 (Folder 84, Box 9)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River 1967; Cornwall 8/21/67 -10/24/67; Numbered 1,319 - 1,503 (Folder 85, Box 9)
  - Fish Capture Report, Hudson River 1967; Cornwall (Co.) 24 hour Site; 8/10/67 - 9/21/67; Numbered 1,504 - 1,669 (Folder 86, Box 9)
  - Collections not available; Coxsackie 1967; Fish Capture Report, Hudson River 1967; Coxsackie 6/14/67 - 10/6/67; Numbered 1,670 - 1,743 (Folder 87, Box 9)
  - Collections w/out original data sheets, Croton, 1967; Fish Capture Report Hudson River, 1967; Croton 6/15/67 - 12/14/67; Numbered 1,744 - 1,823 (Folder 88, Box 9)
  - Collections not available, Marlboro, 1967; Fish Capture Report Hudson River, 1967; Marlboro 6/15/67 - 10/21/67; Numbered 2,369 - 2,448 (Folder 89, Box 9)
  - Collections not found; Peekskill 1967; Fish Capture Report, Hudson River, 1967; Peekskill 6/15/67 - 10/21/67; Numbered 2,449 - 2,519 (Folder 90, Box 9)
  - Collections not available, Saugerties 1967; Fish Capture Report, Hudson River, 1967; Saugerties 6/14/67 - 10/13/67; Numbered 2,520 - 2,578 (Folder 91, Box 9)
  - Corrections for the Egg&Larvae Data - Hudson River, 5/10/67 7/27/67 (Folder 92, Box 9)
  - Time/Shape of Fish, 1966; Various Locations (Folder 93, Box 9)
  - Additional Larvae Found…1966, Various Locations (Folder 94, Box 9)
  - Kingston, 1967; Collections 5/16/67 - 6/13/67 (Folder 95, Box 9)
  - Various Locations; Collections, April through August, 1966 (Folder 96, Box 9)
  - Cornwall, Trawl 1967; Collections w/out original sheet (Folder 97, Box 9)
  - Empty Vials - dried up or not used (Folder 98, Box 9)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Trawl) July 1966; Numbered 1-84 (Folder 99, Box 9)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Trawl) August 1966; Numbered 85-166 (Folder 100, Box 9)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Trawl) August 1966; Numbered 167-312 (Folder 101, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Trawl) September 1966; Numbered 313-458 (Folder 102, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Trawl) October 1966 Numbered 459-582 (Folder 103, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Trawl) November 1966 Numbered 583-650 (Folder 104, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Seine) March-July 1966 Numbered 651-697 (Folder 105, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Seine) August 1966 Numbered 698-743 (Folder 106, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Seine) September 1966 Numbered 744-801 (Folder 107, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Seine) October 1966 Numbered 802-864 (Folder 108, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River; Cornwall (Seine) November 1966 Numbered 865-890 (Folder 109, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River, Seine; August - November 1966; Coxsackie; Numbered 891-927 (Folder 110, Box 10)
  - Various Location Data; Fish Capture, Hudson River, Seine; Aug-Nov 1966; Croton; Numbered 928-969 (Folder 111, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River, Seine; August-November 1966; Hyde Park; Numbered 970-998 (Folder 112, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River, Seine; August-November 1966; Kingston; Numbered 999-1046 (Folder 113, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River, Seine; August-November 1966; Marlboro; Numbered 1047-1091 (Folder 114, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River, Seine; August-November 1966; Peekskill; Numbered 1092-1126 (Folder 115, Box 10)
  - Fish Capture, Hudson River, Seine; August-November 1966; Saugerties; Numbered 1127-1154 (Folder 116, Box 10)
  - Fish Collection Data (Notes); Fish Capture, Hudson River, Seine; August-November 1966; Various Locations; Numbered 1155-1190 (Folder 117, Box 10)
- 6. Reports and Temperature Studies, 1966 - 1968; 6; Boxes: 11 - 12 Folders: 118 - 130d
  - 1967 Indian Point Temperature Study; 4/4/67 - 4/27/67 (Folder 118, Box 11)
  - Hudson River Thermal Discharge Study, Indian Point Temperature Study Data Sheets; 6/29/66 - 7/19/66 (Folder 119, Box 11)
  - Hudson River Thermal Discharge Study; Indian Point, April 1966, Ebb Tide and Flood Tide Data (Folder 120, Box 11)
  - Hudson River Indian Point Temperature Study Progress Report, 7/15/66; Map B 173400 (2 Copies); Con Ed Indian Point Generating Station (Folder 121, Box 11)
  - Indian Point Temperature study; handwritten notes and Map Sketches (Folder 122, Box 11)
  - Photos 7/1/66; Con Ed Plant, Indian Point; 6 photos w/ 6 matching negatives (Folder 123, Box 11)
  - Report - “Investigation of the Effects of Cooling Water Upon Hudson River Water Temperatures” 8/3/66 (3 Copies) w/ accompanying maps (Folder 124, Box 11)
  - Report “Hudson River Infra-Red Temperature Study” Ground Control Data at Indian Point; Oct. 25, 26, 28, 1967; Temperature Study Data Collection Sheets and handwritten notes accompanying report (Folder 125, Box 11)
  - Hudson River Infra-red Temperature Study; Ground Control data at Indian Point; April 6,1968; Three enclosure letters to William Bannon at Con Ed of New York (Folder 126, Box 11)
  - Indian Point Field Studies, Velocity Study; August 1968; Con Ed Hydraulic Lab; handwritten notes and two letters to William Bannon at Con Ed of New York (Folder 127, Box 11)
  - Plant Effect Studies; 6/25/68 - 7/25/68; Book 1 of 4 (only copy) (Folder 128, Box 11)
  - Plant Effect Studies; 7/25/68 - 8/12/68; Book 2 of 4 (3 copies) (Folder 129, Box 11)
  - Plant Effect Studies; 8/12/68 - 9/5/68; Book 3 of 4 (copy one) (Folder 130a, Box 12)
  - Plant Effect Studies; 8/12/68 - 9/5/68; Book 3 of 4 (copy two) (Folder 130b, Box 12)
  - Plant Effect Studies; 8/12/68 - 9/5/68; Book 3 of 4 (copy three) (Folder 130c, Box 12)
  - Plant Effect Studies; 8/12/68 - 9/5/68; Book 3 of 4 (copy four) (Folder 130d, Box 12)